In a world of secrets, love is the most powerful weapon.
Blue Sky is a drama, romance film directed by Tony Richardson.
Hank Marshall is a tough, square-jawed, straitlaced Army engineer and nuclear science
expert, assigned to help conduct weapons testing in 1950s America.
Hank has become a thorn in the side of the Army, though,
for a couple of very different reasons.
He is an outspoken opponent of atmospheric testing, though his superiors hold
contrary views and want to squelch his concerns...and his reports.
The other problem is his wife, Carly.
She is voluptuous and volatile, wreaking havoc in his personal
life and stirring up intrigue at each new Army base.
Carly Marshall, played by Jessica Lange.
Hank Marshall, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Vince Johnson, played by Powers Boothe.
Vera Johnson, played by Carrie Snodgress.
Alex Marshall, played by Amy Locane.
Glenn Johnson, played by Chris O'Donnell.
Blue Sky is a 1994 American comedy-drama film directed by Tony Richardson and
written by Rama Laurie Stagner, Arlene Sarner, and Jerry Leichtling.
The film stars Jessica Lange and Tommy Lee Jones, with supporting performances from Powers
Boothe, Carrie Snodgress, Amy Locane, Chris O'Donnell, and Mitchell Ryan.
Set in the 1960s, the story follows a U.S.
Army engineer who becomes entangled in a military nuclear cover-up while navigating
the challenges posed by his wife's increasingly erratic behavior.
The film was inspired by the real-life experiences of screenwriter Rama
Laurie Stagner's parents during her father's military service.
Blue Sky was Richardson's final film before his death in 1991,
and its release was delayed until September 1994.
Though a box office disappointment, the film received generally positive
reviews, with particular praise for Lange's performance.
She won the Academy Award for Best Actress, as well as a Golden Globe Award, becoming the
second actress to win both Best Supporting Actress and Best Actress Oscars.
The film's score was composed by Jack Nitzsche.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, alabama,
nuclear missile, hand grenade, military base.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.